Guide to the Richard L. Purdy Collection of Thomas Hardy
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Richard L. Purdy Collection of Thomas Hardy
1753-1981
GEN MSS 111
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
20.15
(32 boxes)
The Richard L. Purdy Collection of Thomas Hardy consists of letters, manuscripts, and associated materials by and about the life of Thomas Hardy. Also included are papers from Sydney C. Cockerell, an associate of Hardy's, and also representative items from other English authors and artists such as Robert Browning and Alfred Lord Tennyson.
Purdy, Richard Little, 1904-1990
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The collection was officially bequeathed to the Beinecke Library in 1991, following the death of Professor Purdy.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
RICHARD L. PURDY (1904-1990)
Richard Little Purdy was born in Middletown, New York on April 21, 1904. He was graduated from Yale College with a Bachelor of Arts degree in 1925, followed by a Ph.D from Yale Graduate School in 1930. Purdy held the position of Associate Professor of English at Yale University and fellow of Berkeley College, acting from time to time as assistant to the Keeper of Rare Books for the University Library (1931-36), adviser on Victorian literature (1954-70), and chief marshall for the Yale commencement exercises (1962-70).
While organizing an exhibition of Thomas Hardy materials for the Yale University Library in 1928, Purdy entered into correspondence with Florence Hardy and started his personal collection of Thomas Hardy books, manuscripts and memorabilia. As his research proceeded on a definitive bibliography of Hardy's works, Purdy came to know Howard Bliss, Sydney Cockerell, Dorothy Allhusen, and several other of Hardy's contemporaries. Purdy first gained recognition as a Hardy scholar in 1940 when he announced that the biographies of Hardy supposedly written by Florence Hardy were, in fact, written by Hardy during his lifetime and finished by her. Purdy's Thomas Hardy: A Bibliographical Study, was published in 1954.
Though principally known as a Hardy scholar, Purdy also wrote about and collected other writers, including Robert Browning, Christina and Dante Gabriel Rossetti, and Alfred Lord Tennyson. His edition of Sheridan's The Rivals from the original Larpent manuscript was published in 1935 by the Clarendon Press. After his retirement from Yale in 1970, Purdy continued research on Thomas Hardy, publishing, with Michael Millgate, The Collected Letters of Thomas Hardy in seven volumes between 1978-88. Richard L. Purdy died in Chatham, New Jersey, on August 7, 1990.
Scope and Contents
The Richard L. Purdy Collection of Thomas Hardy consists of manuscripts, letters, photographs, graphic materials, and printed materials, most of which relate to the life and works of Thomas Hardy (1840-1928). A group of papers from Hardy's literary executor, Sydney Cockerell, is included in this archive. The collection also contains manuscripts and memorabilia pertaining to others. The collection spans the years 1753-1981; the bulk derives from the years of Hardy's most prolific writing, 1880-1927.
The collection is housed in 30 boxes and is divided into six series: Writings of Thomas Hardy; Thomas Hardy Correspondence; Thomas Hardy Association Material; Thomas Hardy Research Material; Sydney C. Cockerell Papers; and Non-Hardy Material. Boxes 26-30 contain Oversize material.
Series I, Writings of Thomas Hardy, holds a representative sampling of manuscript materials, including holograph items such as the poems "The Division," "A Jingle on the Times," "A Last Leaving" and "Yellow-hammer," and corrected proofs for the serialized version of The Hand of Ethelberta. Among the rarer items from Hardy found in this series are a very early notebook titled "Studies, Specimens, &c." (dating from the 1860s) and a facsimile of "Dorothy Allhusen's Appeal Letter." In addition to the holographic materials, Purdy also collected clippings which appeared in newspapers and magazines during Hardy's lifetime. These include poems and letters to the editor. Several privately printed pamphlets of Hardy poems, most of which, as with "Yuletide in a Younger World," are present in proof and final printed versions, are also held. A brief subseries of Writings of Others contains four printed items concerning Hardy and a proof of Lady Grove's The Social Fetich, corrected by Hardy and accompanied by letters from him and from Emma Hardy.
Series II contains Thomas Hardy Correspondence. Most of the letters found here have been published in Richard Purdy and Michael Millgate's Collected Letters of Thomas Hardy. Unidentified letters are so listed in the Collected Letters.... The first subseries contains letters addressed to Hardy; the second, letters written by him; the third, third party correspondence between Hardy's contemporaries and associates. Family members are well-represented by such correspondents as Edward, Emma, and Constance Dugdale and Emma, Florence, and Katharine Hardy. Purdy's collection features a number of early letters from Hardy to Havelock Ellis, George Du Maurier, Thomas Macquoid, Edward Marston, John Morley, Handley Moule, and William Moy Thomas. More extensive files of letters to Dorothy Allhusen, George Gissing, Sir George Forrest, Lady Grove, Mary Jeune (later Lady St. Helier), Nancy Meugens, Arthur Wing Pinero, William Strang and Arthur Symons can also be found here. The subseries Third Party correspondence contains correspondence of Emma Hardy, Florence Hardy, and Dorothy Allhusen with, among others, E. M. Forster, J. M. Barrie, Sir George Douglas, Howard Bliss, and T. E. Lawrence.
Series III, Thomas Hardy Association Material, contains other Hardy memorabilia collected by Richard Purdy. These are arranged by medium and include leaves from diaries from Eva Dugdale and Florence Hardy, scrapbooks from Constance Dugdale, a watercolor by Thomas Hardy, a floor plan for an antique building by Thomas Hardy, a portrait of Hardy by Reginald Eves and bookplates for the Max Gate Library. Among the photographs are scenes of Dorchester, portraits of Florence Hardy and Max Gate, and various poses of Thomas Hardy with admirers. This series also contains a number of programs for plays adapted from Thomas Hardy's writings.
Series IV consists of Thomas Hardy Research Material. Among the nine subseries are articles, four boxes of auction and booksellers' catalogs featuring Hardy material, and clippings from newspapers and magazines. The correspondence subseries documents Purdy's contacts with associates and the Hardy family, including files of correspondence with Dorothy Allhusen, Howard Bliss, Constance Dugdale, Ethel Dugdale-Richardson, Eva Dugdale, Florence Hardy, and Margaret and Tom Soundy. The remaining subseries consist of ephemera (including family trees of Hardy and related families), printed material, subject files (which include documents concerning Thomas Hardy's supposed illegitimate son and the "Old Clock" poem controversy), wills from several members of Hardy's family, and writings by Purdy, including his manuscript notebooks and loose notes describing his meetings with Florence Hardy and Sydney Cockerell. Complementing these notes are transcripts of letters sent by Purdy to his parents during his trips to England. These are classified as part of the Correspondence section.
Series V, Sydney Cockerell Papers, consists of items gathered by Purdy from Sydney Cockerell. Most of these materials complement Richard Purdy's own research materials. The correspondence subseries includes letters from Howard Bliss, Florence Hardy, Katharine Hardy, and Thomas Hardy. Among the few items in Cockerell's third party correspondence are a letter written by Florence Hardy to John Hornby and a letter written by T. E. Lawrence to John Hornby. Other material includes clippings about Hardy, notes on Cockerell's interaction with Hardy's publishers, a Hardy poem in Cockerell's hand, a variety of printed ephemera, including several theater programs, and copies of Florence and Thomas Hardy's wills.
Series, VI, Non-Hardy Material, is comprised of a variety of letters, manuscripts and graphic items relating mainly to English literary and artistic figures of the 18th and 19th centuries, also collected by Purdy. They include five letters each from Matthew Arnold and Robert Browning, three letters each from Arthur H. Hallam and Christina Rossetti, 11 letters from Dante Gabriel Rossetti to Theodore Watts-Dunton, 29 letters between George Smith and Leslie Stephen, and four letters from Alfred Lord Tennyson to Robert Monteith. Among the Writings are Robert Browning manuscript fragments, corrected works by Henry Reed, two holograph pieces by Alfred Lord Tennyson, and a copy of a speech delivered by Queen Victoria on the opening of the Royal Albert Hall, in the hand of Lt. General Grey. The few miscellaneous items include a scrapbook of American greeting and business promotional cards, two handcolored early American folding verses for children, items from an album by Browning's friend, André-Victor-Amédée, marquis de Ripert-Monclar, and photographs of Dante Gabriel Rossetti's tombstone and of Richard Wagner. Many of these items are accompanied by correspondence and/or receipts from the vendor to Richard Purdy.
An additional series added in September, 1999, Series VII. Materials removed from Printed Items, contains materials previously contained in printed items, which have been cataloged separately.
We wish to acknowledge with gratitude the valuable input received from Michael Millgate in the editing of this register. Subsequent identification of materials and instances of reorganization account for the number of "Empty folders" in the listing.
Authors, English -- Archives; Browning, Robert, 1812-1889; Cockerell, Sydney Carlyle, Sir, 1867-1962; Hardy, Emma Lavinia Gifford, 1840-1912; Hardy, Florence Emily, 1879-1937; Hardy, Thomas, 1840-1928; Purdy, Richard Little, 1904-1990; Tennyson, Alfred Tennyson, Baron, 1809-1892
- Writings of Thomas Hardy, 1856-1966; Series I; 1; (2 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  Series I is arranged alphabetically by title.
  - Address - "Dorset in London" - The Society of Dorset Men in London Yearbook, printed version, 1908 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "After the Visit," holograph, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - "Ah, Are You Digging on my Grave?" Saturday Review, printed version, 1913 Sep 27 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - "Any Little Old Song," printed sheet, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - "At A House in Hampstead: Sometime a Dwelling of John Keats," facsimile reproduction of holograph, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - "Before and After Summer," printed version, New Weekly, 1914 Apr 4 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Biographical article on Thomas Hardy, typescript, corrected, [ca.1900] (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - "The Bird-Catcher's Boy," typescript in envelope to "Miss Dugdale", 1925 Feb 19 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Black's Guide to Dorset: [Notes on the Wessex Novels] holograph by Emma Hardy and Thomas Hardy (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - [bound with letter from Thomas Hardy to Bertram Windle], 1896 Sep 28
  - A Book of Remembrance: "Foreword", Typescript, corrected, photocopy. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - [with letters from Alfred Pope to Richard Purdy, 1928 and clippings], 1919
  - "By the Century's Deathbed," printed version, Graphic (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - [inscribed by Hardy], 1900 Dec 29
  - Check, cancelled, signed by Thomas Hardy (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - [with note], 1926 Mar 29
  - "A Christmas Ghost Story," printed version [ Westminster Gazette ?], [1899 Dec 23] (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - "Christmas in the Elgin Room," typescript, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Collected Poems, reviews, 1919 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - "The Crime of Rheims" [Letter to the Daily News and Leader], printed version, 1914 Oct 7 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - "The Division," holograph, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - "Dorothy Allhusen's Appeal Letter," [1918 Oct], holograph manuscript and facsimile (with letters from Dorothy Allhusen to Richard Purdy 1937 Aug 20 and 1937 Sep 29 - and from Florence Hardy to Dorothy Allhusen 1918 Oct 4) (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - "The Dorset Farm Labourer," rough proof, corrected (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - [with bookseller's notes], 1884
  - The Dynasts, "A German Dissertation on the Dynasts " by A. W. G. Randall, review, The Saturday Westminster Gazette, 1920 Jul 31
    Related Archival Materials note
    See: Oversize, Box 26, folder 822
  - "Epitaph on a Pessimist," printed version, [ London Mercury ?] (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - The Famous Tragedy of the Queen of Cornwall, bookjacket, [1923] (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Far From the Madding Crowd
    - Chapters XI and XII, printed version, Every Saturday, 1874 Apr 11 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - (Dramatization) page of dialogue, holograph with typed transcripts, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - "The Farm-Woman's Winter", printed version, Pall Mall Magazine, title page only, 1905 Jan (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - "The Fiddler of the Reels," printed version, Scribner's Magazine, title page only, 1893 May (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - "The Fiddler's Story and a Jingle on the Times" (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Typescripts, 1914 Dec
    - 1st proof for pamphlet, corrected, 1917 Oct
    - Pamphlet [with letters from Florence Hardy to Sydney Cockerell 1917 Sep 8 and Oct 2], 1917 Oct
  - Forewords - Society of Dorset Men in London Yearbook, printed version, [1907] (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - "G.M.: A Reminiscence" (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Proof for The Nineteenth Century and After, corrected, 1927 Oct 31
    - 1st proof for pamphlet, 1927 Nov 9
    - 2nd proof for pamphlet, 1927 Nov
    - Pamphlet [with letter from Florence Hardy to Sydney Cockerell], 1927 Nov 21
  - [General Works], "Hardy's Works" by Richard Church [review], printed version, The Spectator, 1928 Jan 21 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - "A Glimpse from the Train," London Mercury, printed version, 1920 Jan (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - "Going and Staying," London Mercury, printed version, 1919 Nov (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - "A Great Thought" ["What does it matter, When you care to think of it...], printed version, The Save the Children Fund Pictorial, 1928 Jun (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - The Hand of Ethelberta, proof sheets for The Cornhill Magazine, corrected (Box 1, Folder 33-33a)
    - [with bookseller's correspondence with Richard Purdy, 1944], 1875-76
  - Human Shows, Far Phantasies, book jacket, [1925] (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Human Shows [fragment], holograph (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - [negatives made to bring out erasures], 1868, n.d.
  - Human Shows and Winter Words, book jacket, [1931] (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - "A Hundred Years Since," typescript (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - "In the Evening," typescript, photocopy, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - "Interlopers at the Knap," English Illustrated Magazine, 1884 May (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - "A Jingle on the Times" (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Manuscript, holograph, corrected, 1914 Dec 13
    - Printed version, 1917 Oct
  - Jude the Obscure
    - Preface (titled "Postscript") holograph (with notes by Richard Purdy), 1911 Oct (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Proof pages, corrected, photostat, with letter from Robert C. Slack to Richard Purdy [also includes cover letter from George F. Stewart, ca. 1945], 1895, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Review, "Stilted Speeches" by St. John Ervine, printed version. T. P.'s Weekley, 1927 Nov 19 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - "The Lady in the Christmas Furs," New York Herald Tribune, printed version, 1927 Aug 21 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - "A Last Leaving," holograph, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Late Lyrics and Earlier and the Famous Tragedy of the Queen of Cornwall, book jacket, [1926] (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Late Lyrics and Earlier, review, 1922 May 23 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Letter to the Editor from "the Wareham Town Pump" (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - printed version, Southern Times, 1856 Mar 1
    - printed version, Dorset County Chronicle, 1856 Mar 6
  - "An Appeal from Dorset," letter to the editor, New York Herald Tribune, printed version, 1926 Apr 25 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - "Lines, Spoken by Miss Ada Rehan..." holograph (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - [with note], 1890 Jul 20
  - "List of Miscellaneous Articles," holograph photostats (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - [with notes], 1960, n.d.
  - "Lizard", holograph, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - "The Love Letter" (in memoriam H.R.), holograph, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - The Mayor of Casterbridge, drawings by Robert Barnes, photocopies, n.d.
  - "Messages to our Readers from Men of Distinction," The Shop Assistant, printed version, 1919 Jun 21 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - "Mr. Hardy's Poems" [Letter to the editor of The Daily News ], printed version, 1909 Dec 15 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Moments of Vision, book jacket, ca. 1917 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - "Morning Hymn," by Barthélémon, holograph, copied by Thomas Hardy for Mrs. Dugdale, 1914 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - "The Newspaper Soliloquizes," The New York Times, printed version, 1926 Mar 13 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - "No Bell Ringing: A Ballad of Durnover"
    - proof sheet, corrected, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - printed version, The Sphere, photocopy, 1925 Nov 23
  - Note accompanying Horace Moule's "Ave Caesar,", 1922 Oct
    See: Writings of Others - Horace Moule, Box 2 folder 105
  - Notes on The Wessex of Thomas Hardy by Hermann Lea - holograph photostat (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - [with notes by Richard Purdy], 1913-48
  - Obituary of Mary Hardy (printed, corrected by TH), n.d. (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - "On the Century's Deathbed," holograph (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - [in the hand of Richard Purdy]
  - "On the Departure Platform," holograph photocopy, 1909 Dec (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - "One We Knew," The Tatler, printed version, 1903 Dec 2 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - "Our Exploits at West Poley", printed version, The Household, photocopy, 1892-93
    See: Oversize, Box 26, folder 823
  - "The Oxen" in Christmas Flowers, printed version, 1952 Dec (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - "The Peace Peal," The Graphic, printed version, photocopy, 1919 Dec (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - "Performing Animals," letter to the editor of the Times, printed version, 1913 Dec 19 (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - "The Plaint of Certain Spectres," The Saturday Review, printed version, 1914 Jan 3 (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - "The Play of Saint George," proof, corrected (Box 2, Folder 69)
    - [with letter from Florence Hardy to Sydney Cockerell 1921 Mar 21], 1921 Mar 31
  - "The Portraits" (Box 2, Folder 70)
    - typescript, 1945 Jul
    - Nash's & Pall Mall Magazine, printed version, 1924 Dec
  - "Proposed Restoration of the Church of St. Juliot," typescript [typed by Howard Bliss], 1866-1962 (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - "Psalm CI" by Dr. Crotch, holograph, copied by Thomas Hardy, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - "A Question of Priority" [Letter to The Westminster Gazette ], printed version, 1893 May 10 (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - Response to inquiry, "Contrainte et liberté" printed version, L'Ermitage, 1893 Nov (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - Response to inquiry ["La France est-elle en décadence?"], printed version, L'Européen, photocopy, 1904 Mar 26
  - [Response to Solicitation - Letter to the Editor], printed version, The Old Cambridge, 1920 Feb 28 (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - The Return of the Native
    - Compilation of remarks from reviews, typescript, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 76)
    - Serialization in Belgravia, removed sections [incomplete], 1878 (Box 2, Folder 77)
  - "The Sacrilege," The Fortnight Review, printed version, 1911 Nov 1 (Box 2, Folder 78)
  - "Serial Rights in Stories" [letter to The Athenaeum ], printed version, 1903 May 16 (Box 2, Folder 79)
  - "Song of the Soldiers" The Weekly Dispatch, printed version, 1914 Sep 23 (Box 2, Folder 80)
  - "Studies, Specimens, &c."
    - Notebook, ca. 1865 (Box 2, Folder 81)
    - [Transcript showing sources, typescript, possibly made by Richard Purdy, with index], 1971 (Box 2, Folder 82)
  - Tess of the D'Urbervilles
    - The Graphic, printed version, 1891 Jul 4 (Box 2, Folder 83)
    - Review by L. F. Austin, printed version, The Album, 1895 May 6 (Box 2, Folder 84)
    - Review by P. and Q., The World, photocopy, 1892 Jan 13
  - "Thomas Hardy's Graphic Description of Maiden Castle," printed version, The Detroit Post, photocopy, 1885 Mar 15
    See: Oversize, Box 26, folder 824
  - Time's Laughingstocks, review, printed version, Daily News, 1909 Dec 13 (Box 2, Folder 85)
  - "To Shakespeare After Three Hundred Years"
    - 1st proof for pamphlet, corrected, 1916 (Box 2, Folder 86)
    - 2nd proof for pamphlet, 1916
    - Pamphlet [signed by Florence Hardy] [with letter from Florence Hardy to Sydney Cockerell 1916 Jul 30]
  - Under the Greenwood Tree [fragment] holograph [photograph] (Box 2, Folder 87)
  - "Vagrant's Song," typescript, 1945 Jul (Box 2, Folder 88)
  - [Various Works] Announcements, The Review of Reviews, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 89)
  - "A Victorian Rehearsal," holograph, corrected [facsimile published in Times Literary Supplement ], 1966 Jun 2 (Box 2, Folder 90)
  - "Voices from Things Growing," London Mercury, printed version, 1921 Feb (Box 2, Folder 91)
  - "Weathers," typescript [supplied to Richard Purdy by "the publishers"], 1945 Jul (Box 2, Folder 92)
  - "When I Weekly Knew" (Box 2, Folder 93)
    - Typescript, 1916
    - 1st proof for pamphlet, 1916 May 10
    - Pamphlet, 1916
  - "The Wife of Thomas Hardy," holograph [in the hand of Emma Hardy], [1892 Nov 24] (Box 2, Folder 94)
  - Winter Words
    - Advertisement, ca. 1928 (Box 2, Folder 95)
    - Selections, Daily Telegraph, printed version [with notes by Richard Purdy and receipt], 1928, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 96)
  - "Wives in the Sere," The Tatler, printed version, 1901 Jul 31 (Box 2, Folder 97)
  - "The Woman I Met," London Mercury, printed version, 1921 Apr (Box 2, Folder 98)
  - Word-definitions Written by Thomas Hardy in... O.E.D. (typescript list by David Holmes), n.d. (Box 2, Folder 99)
  - "Yellow-hammer", holograph, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 100)
  - "Yuletide in a Younger World," typescript, proofs and printed sheet, 1927 (Box 2, Folder 101)
    - Writings of Others
      - Colvin, Ian, "An Elegy," The Morning Post, printed version, 1928 Jan 16 (Box 2, Folder 102)
      - Grove, Agnes Geraldine, Lady, The Social Fetich, proof, corrected by Thomas Hardy, 1908 (Box 2, Folder 103)
        [includes: Letters from Thomas Hardy to Lady Grove, 1908 Aug 8, 11 & 16, Sep 4, & Dec 3 and undated; Letter from Emma Hardy to Lady Grove 1907 Dec 9]
      - Hardy, Emma, "Some Recollections," page proof, 1961 Jul (Box 2, Folder 104)
      - Moule, Horace, "Ave Caesar," The London Mercury, printed version, 1922 Oct (Box 2, Folder 105)
      - Moulton, Louise, "On Egdon Heath," New York Herald Tribune, printed version, 1928 Mar 18 (Box 2, Folder 106)
- Thomas Hardy Correspondence, 1873-1971; Series II; 1.25; (3 boxes)
  Series II is arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent. This listing also includes cross-references to significant bodies of correspondence housed elsewhere in the collection.
  - INCOMING LETTERS
    - Cross, Wilbur L., 1920 May 10 (Box 3, Folder 107)
    - Drinkwater, John, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 108)
    - Galsworthy, John, 1910 Aug 10 (Box 3, Folder 109)
    - Grand, Sarah, 1919 Apr 16 (Box 3, Folder 110)
    - Hardy, Mary, 1914 Feb 8 (Box 3, Folder 111)
    - Masefield, John, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 112)
    - Purdy, Richard L. [draft], 1927 Oct 19 (Box 3, Folder 113)
    - Terry, Marion [to Emma Hardy], 1883
      See: Series III, Scrapbooks, Box 7 folder 332e
  - OUTGOING LETTERS
    - Allhusen, Dorothy, 1892-1927 (Box 3, Folder 114-15)
    - Allhusen, Elizabeth, 1924 Jan 7 (Box 3, Folder 116)
    - Bagot, Richard, 1917 Jun 7 (Box 3, Folder 117)
    - Bainton, Rev. George, 1889 Oct 11 (Box 3, Folder 118)
    - Baxter, Lucy, 1888 Jan 26 (Box 3, Folder 119)
    - Bell, Moberly, 1909 Nov 5 (Box 3, Folder 120)
    - Black, William, 1890 Dec 21 (Box 3, Folder 121)
    - Blanchamp, H., 1891 Mar 6 (Box 3, Folder 122)